Filinkov Ivan

Lead Technical Writer

Tbilisi, Georgia



Ivan@filinkov.org filinkov.org

Summary

I have been leading teams for 3 years. I excel at establishing processes, writing clear documentation, and building partnerships with clients. I am skilled at adapting text to the target audience and finding common ground with experts of different levels. With 6 years of experience in technical support, I can install LAMP, write SQL queries, and test APIs. I enjoy organizing things and I'm a bit of a perfectionist.

Work experience

Lead Technical Writer, 01.2021 — 03.2023

<u>r_keeper</u> (VK, O2O) — Russian biggest restaurant automation software company with over 65.000 restaurants in 53 different countries.

Estabilished documentation processes, popularizing it among users and clients.

- Configured Confluence Server from scratch and organized migration of all documentation to it;
- Implemented a Jira process with text cross validation and reports in EasyBI;
- Created and reviewed marketing texts for the blog, email, and social media.
- Established user feedback channels, created 2 Telegram channels, and a documentation chat with a total audience of 700 people.

Technical Writer, 12.2018-12.2020

r_keeper (VK, O2O)

I wrote documentation and personally trained clients, helping them understand our product.

Documentation

- Created a style guide for technical writers. All articles are now written according to it.
- Migrate the knowledge base from an old Windows server to Ubuntu. The loading speed increased by 2-4 times.

Training

- Developed and filmed a series of training videos that eliminated the need for in-person training. The onboarding time for new dealers reduced from 3 to 1 day.
- Created educational courses and tests that helped for the identification of unqualified dealers.

Freelance, 06.2017-11.2018

I created educational courses, email and advertising campaigns and also helped small clients with promotion.

- Creating of educational courses on the LMS platform. Holding webinars and video editing.
- Creating mailing lists in Mailchimp and SendPulse.
- Making advertising campaigns on Facebook and Instagram.

Support 2-nd line engineer, 02.2013–05.2017

onlanta.ru is an outsourcing company, part of the LANIT Group, which is the largest IT company in Russia with 14,000 employees and a turnover of 216 billion rubles.

I managed a project for the 1-st and 2-nd line technical support for a chain of retail stores.

- Project management, communicating with the clients, creating roadmaps and action plans.
- Resolving incidents: remote support, installation, replacement, and repair of equipment.
- Writing instructions and employees training.

Additional Information

Education: Specialist degree, MGUPP, 2012. Engineering Technologist Languages: English — B2, upper intermediate, Russian — native.

Certification: ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management, 2016